# **Bailey Segail**

segailbailev@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/bailev-segail/ | +61 410 127 241

#### **PROFILE**

Purpose driven, senior engineer that leads teams and aligns business goals, project outcomes, and user needs when creating digital products. Track record of delivering success for web and mobile projects for startups, enterprises and non-profits.

I love building and scaling MVPs. I have a strong passion for user experience design, and enjoy finding the balance between design and engineering. I was most recently Engineering Lead for the BIG W mobile app for iOS and Android.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UPGROWTH
Technical Lead

Sydney, Australia Jul 2019 - Present

Core role within the digital consultancy group that led projects across enterprise and startups. Crafted enterprise-grade code, prioritised and defined project scope, critically reviewed user experience designs, managed external stakeholders and mentored peers.

## BIG W Mobile App - iOS, Android, TypeScript, React Native, Firebase

- Spearheaded development team and launched the MVP within a 4 month timeframe. Subsequently drove the product to scale with an App Store rating of 4.7 stars.
- Responsible for creating core application screens, API integrations, CMS integration, and developer experience working patterns.
- Established release strategy, CI/CD workflows, and implemented various tools to manage existing public app releases including; A/B testing, runtime config updates, over-the-air updates, forced updates, customer messaging systems, and maintenance modes.
- Guided designers on producing a scalable design system to be used within web and mobile customer channels; informed structure and usage of design tokens, and counselled on component and design pattern reuse.

## BIG W Frontend Website - TypeScript, Next.js, NestJS, Express, Node.js, AWS, MySQL, Vercel

- Responsible for creating the core front-end user journeys for checkout including delivery, and click and collect.
- Created new customer journeys to initiate buy-now-pay-later purchases (layby), and customer journeys for managing instalment repayments; on launch this payment method accounted for 40% of all online sales.
- Created methods to handle server side rendering for Adobe Experience Manager content, and data hydration for custom state management framework to majorly increase overall website load times.

## Ditno - TypeScript, React

- Led development of a web application used by enterprises to manage security governance for their IT infrastructure; completion of the project unlocked the next funding gate for Ditno.
- Created core screens and front end architecture for high performant data visualisation, sorting and filtering.
- Led design reviews and ideated solutions which balanced component reusability, user experience and user interface aesthetics.
- Consulted with the client and guided technical and design decisions that minimised overall cost of development.
- Worked closely with the external backend team to produce scalable API endpoints that allowed for front-end code reuse and minimised load times for users.

#### **FULLSTACK DIGITAL**

Senior Engineer

Co-founded a digital studio that worked with nonprofits, agencies and enterprises. Responsible for technical consulting and leading a cross functional team through project management, collaborative design review, paired programming and mentoring.

#### The Hotel Card - React, Redux, Node.Js, Express, MongoDB, Heroku

- Led development of a customer facing website in 3 months for users to book accommodation at over 800,000 hotels world wide using gift cards bought in retail stores.
- Created core website screens for search and customer booking journeys.
- Created a custom API server to handle authentication, payment and bookings used in the customer facing website and admin portal to manage bookings and refunds.
- Consulted on the best technologies to use given business needs, budgets, timelines and the future vision of the product.

### Dimeo - iOS, Android, React Native, React, JavaScript, Redux, Python, Django, PostgreSQL

- Led development of a mobile application for staff to check-in their location at work sites and track shift time.
- Created Django REST API endpoints to handle authentication and log worker shift time within the mobile app.
- Created an Admin Dashboard that allowed users to onboard different work sites, manage staff shift schedules and see reports and data insights on logged worker shift time.

#### St John NSW Members Web - React, JavaScript, Node.is, Express, MongoDB, Heroku

- Created a web application that allowed SSO staff members to post, view and moderate community updates.
- Created custom API endpoints for SSO authentication, user role management and content management services.
- Created a custom content management system for user generated content and review process

#### **ISLAND PACIFIC**

Sydney, Australia Nov 2015 - Aug 2016

Mobile App Developer

Part of the SmartStore team that was tasked with maintaining and developing software used for retail point of sale transactions.

- Worked closely with the senior developer running the project; fixing bugs, adding new features, and working with the QA team to ensure stable production releases.
- Identified a major code deprecation which required a re-architecture of the app.

## **EDUCATION**

## **MACQUARIE UNIVERSITY**

Sydney, Australia Jan 2016 - Jul 2018

BCom with Marketing and Entrepreneurship Majors\*

\*Deferred degree to work in Fullstack Digital (as above) with no plans to return.

#### **REFERENCES**

References available on request